# Lei Ding

**★** Los Angeles, CA 90024 **★** 310-869-6435

stonre@g.ucla.edu
in linkedin.com/Lei Ding

## **Professional Summary**

Over 4 year software study and experience with solid background in software tool development, web application and machine learning. Led several technical projects with good cooperation ability in team work. Always self-motivated to learn new technologies and work on challenging projects.

#### Education

University of California, Los Angeles Los Angeles, California

Est. Mar 2017

M.S. in Electrical Engineering, Current GPA: 3.5

Shanghai Jiao Tong University (SJTU) Shanghai, China

Jul. 2015

B.S. in Information Engineering, GPA: 3.6

#### Selected Courses

Web Applications, Parallel and Distributed Programming, Operating Systems, Social Network Analysis, Machine Learning Algorithms, Data Structures, Computer Networks, Embedded Systems, Image Processing, Game Theory

#### Experience

#### Software Engineer Intern Amazon

Jun. 2016-Sept. 2016

- Built a data management tool to extract time series inventory data from DynamoDB and S3.
- Designed data schema for storage in DynamoDB and optimized query and write performance with limited read and write capacity.
- Created website for time series analysis using Spring MVC with tools like D3, JQuery, Bootstrap.

#### Undergraduate Research Assistant SJTU

Sept. 2013-Jun. 2015

- Co-built a RSS based indoor localization system with improved accuracy and co-possess a patent.
- Co-led a real-time traffic information sharing system with high (93%) vehicle prediction accuracy.
- Designed and built a testing tool for Ericsson's SDN Dallas system.

## **Selected Projects**

# Rating Prediction of IMDb Movies Based on Social Network Analysis and Machine Learning Algorithm UCLA Mar. 2016-May. 2016

- Constructed IMDb movie and actor networks and did analysis with PageRank and FastGreedy.
- Extracted features from actors' pageranks and movies' community properties.
- Trained a regression model to predict movies' ratings with Gradient Boosting, Random Forest.

# Large Scale Community Detection Based on Spark UCLA

Mar. 2016-May. 2016

- Studied and Implemented Louvain distributed community detection algorithm using Scala.
- Managed a EMR cluster for Spark as the distributed computing platform.
- Tested detection performance (high modularity 0.43) with Twitter user network data.

#### Website Development for Ebay Auction Search UCLA

Jan. 2016-Mar. 2016

- Designed relational auction data schema for storage in MySQL.
- Implemented search functions with Lucene and built a website using Axis2 and Tomcat.
- Added Google Suggest and Map service with AJAX and a secure transaction service with SSL.

#### Skills

- Language: Java, C++, JavaScript, Python, C, R, Matlab, HTML, SQL
- Tools: JQuery, D3, NodeJs, BootStrap